foot-patrol.com 2018-01-25

# Privacy Policy | Footpatrol

#### About Us

Footpatrol is part of the JD Sports Fashion Group and, for the purposes of the information which you provide to us, acts as the data controller. This means that we are responsible for what happens to the information that you give to us. We will at all times comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 and make sure that we keep your data secure and steps are taken to prevent any unauthorised access to your information. From time to time, we will share the information which you provide to us with other group companies within the JD Sports Fashion Group.

The JD Sports Fashion Group is constantly growing and changing. We will always update the web page [here](http://www.jdplc.com/our-group/sports-fashion.aspx), so you should take a look from time to time to see if new companies have joined the group or if any company leaves our group.

#### What data do we collect?

We collect all of the information which you submit to us. For example, when you sign up to receive our newsletter or when you communicate with us in any way (for example, email, Facebook, Twitter or in one of our stores). This information will include any passwords, usernames, contact details, account details, preferences, interests and details of any complaints you may have made. We will also collect information when you buy from us on our website or in one of our stores. This will include the time and date of your purchase, the goods you purchased and details of any relevant payment card you used

From time to time we may access publically available information about you on the internet to assist in fraud prevention, for identity verification (such as to confirm we have the correct address details for you) and for marketing purposes, as set out in more detail below..

We also look at your activity on our website, for example what device you're using and what products you're looking at. Much of this information is collected by cookies. For full details, have a look at our [cookie policy](https://www.footpatrol.com/cookies).

#### What do we do with your data?

We use your data to fulfil any orders you place with us. We also share your data with third party service providers who help us to do this and to generally operate our business effectively.  
For example, to help improve the level of service which we provide to you, your data may be shared with third party, independent review websites such as Trustpilot and Feefo. If you want to provide us with feedback on your experience, such third parties may contact you via email to give you the option to do this. You can always leave your feedback anonymously, if you would prefer.

We also use your data for marketing purposes which may mean that you will receive marketing communications from us, other companies within the JD Sports Fashion Group or carefully selected third parties. However if you do receive marketing communications from other companies, we will endeavour to ensure that the company in question and its products will be as relevant to you as possible.

#### How do i manage my data and what you do with it?

We always give you the choice of whether or not you wish to receive marketing communications from us.

By [contacting us](https://www.footpatrol.com/contact-us) you can tell us that you do not wish to receive marketing communications from us and we will update our records. You can also click on the unsubscribe link in any promotional emails.

If at any time you want to talk to us about your data, for example if you spot a mistake, or if you want to change how we market to you, please also [contact us](https://www.footpatrol.com/contact-us).

#### Cookies

**Collection of Anonymous Data**  
As described above, we sometimes collect anonymous information from visits to our site to help us provide better customer service. For example, we keep track of the domains from which people visit and we also measure visitor activity on this Web Site, but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. We use the information that we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different areas of our Web Site, and to help us make our Web Site more useful to visitors. This includes analysing these logs periodically to measure the traffic through our servers, the number of pages visited and the level of demand for pages and topics of interest. The logs may be preserved indefinitely and used at any time and in any way to prevent security breaches and to ensure the integrity of the data on our servers.

We collect the anonymous information we mentioned above through the use of various technologies, one of which is called "cookies". A cookie is an element of data that a web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive.

#### Customer/User Identification and Log-in

A temporary cookie is currently used to identify a user during the registration and checkout processes. When a user provides a username (email address) and password to "log into" this Web Site, either as an existing or a new user, a temporary cookie is set which identifies the applicable user account.  
This temporary cookie is maintained until the user:

  * Clicks the log out button
  * Closes down their browser session
  * Manually clears the User identification cookie

#### User Log-in Caching

Within this Web Site cookies may in the future be used to save the visitor's password (if and when this facility is provided) so that it does not have to be re-entered at each new visit.  
If the user has chosen "remember login and password", the following two items above will be encoded within cookies:

  * A unique Customer ID
  * A login state

If a "registered" user to this Web Site returns to the site without logging in, the ID stored in the cookie can be used to track the user (unless the user manually deleted the cookie, at which point the server may automatically regenerate another cookie).

#### Basket Functionality

This Web Site also utilises cookies for the identification of baskets. When a user clicks an 'Add to Basket' button for the first time during a browsing session a temporary cookie is set to identify a unique Basket ID for that user.  
Any items that the user chooses to add to the basket are associated with the unique Basket ID until the user either:

  * Closes down their browser session
  * Places an order
  * Removes all items from their current basket
  * Manually clears the Basket Cookie

The temporary cookie is cleared when any of the above events occur.

#### Basket Caching

This Web Site may, at some point in the future utilise non-temporary cookies or (i.e. having a limited or unlimited lifespan) to enable basket identifiers to be stored for longer than a single browsing session. Non-temporary cookies would only be used to enhance the user experience and avoid the need for new basket identifiers to be issued during each new user session. Non-temporary basket cookies would remain until the user:

  * Places an order
  * Removes all items from their current basket
  * Manually clears the Basket Cookie

#### Collection and Anonymous Usage of Personal Data

When we collect personal data from you in connection with a transaction we may extract some information about that transaction in an anonymous format and combine it with other anonymous information. This anonymous information is used and analysed only at an aggregate level to help us understand trends and patters. None of this information is reviewed at an individual level. If you do not want your transaction details used in this manner, you can either disable your cookies or opt-out at the order or request stage.

## Children

If you are aged under 12 then you can not register, or enter any competitions, on this Web Site.

#### Access Right

You have a right to access the personal information held about you. To obtain a copy of the information, please write to us at;

#### Customer Services

Footpatrol  
Hollinsbrook Way  
Pilsworth  
Bury  
BL9 8RR

enclosing a cheque for £10.

#### Other Web Sites

Our Web Site may contain links to other web sites which are outside our control and are not covered by the privacy policy. If you access other sites then using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.
